好的  我准备好答下道题目了
All right, I'm ready for my next question.
在一个犀牛被当宠物养的世界中
In a world where rhinoceroses are domesticated pets,
谁将赢得第二次世界大战
who wins the Second World War?
乌干达
Uganda.
理由
Defend.
肯尼亚会因出口犀牛而崛起
Kenya rises to power on the export of rhinoceroses.
在中非成为一个强大的政权
A Central African power block is formed,
并殖民统治北非和欧洲
colonizing North Africa and Europe.
战争爆发后  谁也负担不起养犀牛的这份奢侈
When war breaks out, no one can afford the luxury of a rhino.
肯尼亚衰落  乌干达雄起
Kenya withers, Uganda triumphs.
回答正确
Correct.
轮到我了
My turn.
在一个钢琴被当做武器而不是乐器的世界中
In a world where a piano is a weapon, not a musical instrument,
斯科特·乔普林会用什么来演奏《枫叶爵士》
on what does Scott Joplin play "The Maple Leaf Rag"?
调谐刺刀
Tuned bayonets.
理由
Defend.
理由不是显而易见吗
Isn't it obvious?
你说得对  我的错
You're right. My apologies.
你们俩在玩什么鬼游戏呢
What the hell are you guys playing?
这是我们发明的一个游戏
It's a game we invented.
我们称它为"反事实游戏"
It's called Counterfactuals.
我们假定一个在某关键方面不同于这里的世界
We postulate an alternate world that differs from ours
然后互相就此发问
in one key aspect and then pose questions to each other.
本游戏适合8至80岁人士
It's fun for ages eight to 80.
一起来玩吧
Join us.
好吧
All right.
我也喜欢脑筋急转弯
I like a good brainteaser.
我来试试吧
Give it a whirl.
你走运了  这道简单
You're in luck, this is an easy one.
在一个人类被高智商巨形海狸统治的世界中
In a world where mankind is ruled by a giant intelligent beaver,
哪种食物再也吃不到了
what food is no longer consumed?
BLT[培根生菜番茄三明治]吗  其中B代表海狸
Uh... a BLT where the "B" stands for beaver?
我也说不准
I don't know.
莱纳德  认真点
Leonard, be serious.
我们在玩游戏呢
We're playing a game here.
我能答出来的  让我想想
I can figure this out. Let's see.
海狸以树皮喂食
Um, well, beavers eat tree bark.
我唯一了解的人类用得着树皮的食物是肉桂
The only tree bark I know that humans consume is cinnamon.
所以我说是肉桂
So, I'll say cinnamon.
错误
Incorrect.
答案很明显是芝士丹麦酥
Obviously, the answer is cheese Danish.
你说啥
What?
在一个被巨形海狸统治的世界中
In a world ruled by a giant beaver,
人类为取悦海狸的统治会修建许多水坝
mankind builds many dams to please the beaver overlord.
哥本哈根因地势低洼会遭遇洪灾
The low-lying city of Copenhagen is flooded.
数万人会死去
Thousands die.
更毁灭的是  丹麦人却从未以自己的名字给糕点命名
Devastated, the Danes never invent their namesake pastry.
怎么会有人连这个都想不到呢
How does one miss that?
这太荒谬了
This is ridiculous.
你们这是在捏造答案
You're just making stuff up.
他输的时候总这样吗
Is he always like this when he loses?
那当然了
Oh, yes.
你要是能目睹08年讨论巨形野牛时的景象就好了
You should've been here for the great giant tantrum of 2008.
你掀的桌子  自己清楚
You bumped the table and you know it.
或许我们应该玩个更适合他能力的游戏
Perhaps it would be kinder to play a game more suited to his abilities.
等会儿你躲猫猫的时候  我们会闭眼数到10
We'll close our eyes and count to ten while you hide.
我回屋了
I'm going to my room.
很好  莱纳德
Very good, Leonard.
但下次你藏哪里无需提前告诉我们
But next time, don't tell us where you're hiding.
生活大爆炸
第四季第三集
你们看到《美国物理学报》关于超固体的论文了吗
Did you guys see the paper in The American Physics Journal on supersolids?
挺有趣的
It's pretty interesting.
这个人从假说...
This guy's working from a hypothesis where...
剧透警报  剧透警报
Spoiler alert! Spoiler alert.
-咋了  -别提前爆料
- What?  - Don't ruin it for me, man.
我为了边蹲便壶边看把PDF文件都打出来了
I printed out a PDF to read on the potty.
便壶  你多大了  五岁吗
On the potty? What are you, five?
就是便便的地方嘛  不然你说该叫什么
It's a potty. What do you call it?
厕所
Toilet.
晚饭桌上这么叫不觉得有点粗俗了吗
That's a little vulgar for the dinner table, don't you think?
那"便壶"就不俗了吗
Oh, and "potty" is okay?
"便壶"多纯真  多可爱啊
"Potty" is innocent. "Potty" is adorable.
那你去便便的地方干啥  嘘嘘吗
What do you do in the potty, wee-wee?
如果我不必"嘣嘣"[大便]的话
If I don't have to boom-boom.
各位好
Greetings.
你们都记得艾米·菲拉·福勒吧
You all remember Amy Farrah Fowler.
-见到你很高兴  -你好
- Nice to see you.  - Hello.
抱歉我们迟到了
Sorry we're late.
对此我必须得承担责任
I must take responsibility.
我不得不半路上买点女性卫生用品
I had to stop for feminine hygiene supplies.
-这样啊  -了解
- Aha.  - Okay.
我认为她正在经期当中
I believe she's experiencing her menses.
实际上  还没到时候
Actually, I'm not.
但为了避免意外  我得时刻带着卫生巾
In order to avoid surprises, I wear them all the time.
-理解  -非常了解
- Aha.  - Okay.
厕所现在听起来顺耳多了是吧
"Toilet's" sounding pretty good now, huh?
瞧啊  这不是谢米嘛
Hey, look, it's Shamy.
谢米
Shamy?
一个幼稚地混合我们名字的做法而已
A juvenile amalgamation of our names.
谢尔顿  艾米  "谢米"
Sheldon, Amy-- Shamy.
这样啊
Oh.
我不喜欢  以后别这么叫了
I don't like that. Don't do that.
好吧  有什么新鲜事吗
All righty. What's new?
我刚才得知你称呼我们为"谢米"
Well, just recently, I learned that you refer to us as Shamy,
而我并不喜欢
and I don't like that.
我了解了  但我想问的其实是你生活上的新鲜事
I got it. But what I was going for was, you know, how's your life?
跟普通人没什么两样
Like everybody else's.
经历着万物的成长  衰败和最终的死亡
Subject to entropy, decay and eventual death.
谢谢你的问候
Thank you for asking.
为何她还没有给我们点餐呢
Why is she not taking our order?
我应该提前通知你的
I should've warned you,
如果想在这里用餐前  必须要经历连串
one has to navigate a labyrinth of social nonsense
繁杂而无用的寒暄
before one can be fed here.
是吗  我以为既然起名叫芝士"工厂"
Really? I assumed an establishment called
做事就能更有效率呢
the Cheesecake Factory would function more efficiently.
那是它们诱骗你来的伎俩
It's how they lure you in.
我想这应该称为"诱饵推销法"
I believe it's called "bait and switch."
好吧  我还是遁走好了
Okay, I'm just gonna walk away,
因为  我不想待在这了
'cause... I don't want to be here.
这真不错啊
So, this is nice.
我们第一次齐聚一堂来吃顿饭
First time we've all gotten together to eat.
你说得对  他果然在进行无聊的饭前寒暄
You're right, he's a festival of humdrum chitchat.
好吧  我没辙了
Okay, that's all I got.
霍华德  你上
Howard, you're up.
谈谈你的工作吧  艾米
Um... tell us about your work, Amy.
我怀疑你听不听得懂
I doubt you'd understand.
谢尔顿告诉我你只有个硕士学位
Sheldon tells me you only have a master's degree.
拉杰  你有没有问题问艾米
Raj, do you have any questions for Amy?
我很好奇  我们怎么不单独吃饭
I'm curious as to why we're not eating alone.
他们离不开我
They can't function without me.
我是凝聚这个小团体的粘合剂
I'm the social glue that holds this little group together.
不用谢我
You're welcome.
我能跟你谈谈你的女朋友吗
Listen, can I talk to you about your girlfriend?
她不是我的女朋友
She's not my girlfriend.
她是女生  也是我朋友
She's a girl and she's my friend,
但绝对没有触摸或不洁的交换唾液
but there's no touching or unsanitary exchange of saliva.
明白
Got it.
不过  倒是有一次
Although, for the record, on one occasion,
她舔了一下拇指  然后帮我抹掉
she licked her thumb to remove raspberry jelly
嘴角上的树莓果冻
from the corner of my mouth.
我们今天都为此后悔不已
It's an action we both regret to this day.
明白
Uh-huh.
不过  我觉得她不太适合
Anyway, I'm not sure she's the best fit
我们这个  怎么说呢  反抗军[星球大战]
for our little-- how should we call it-- rebel alliance.
我一直不认同反抗军
Oh, I never identified with the rebel alliance.
尽管他们想建造死亡星球
Despite their tendency to build Death Stars,
我一直支持银河帝国
I've always been more of an empire man.
那不是我想说的
Yeah, not my point.
我知道你想说什么
I know what your point is.
你们被艾米的智慧吓着了
You're intimidated by Amy's intellect.
我只能说  振作点
To that I say, buck up.
我直接说吧
Okay, let me just get right to it.
艾米很爱批评人  假正经  而且
Amy is judgmental, sanctimonious and frankly...
很讨人厌
just obnoxious.
那又如何
So?
我们已经要忍受这样一个你了
So we already have you for all that.
你这是建议我停止和艾米交往吗
Are you suggesting I terminate my relationship with Amy?
不  当然不是
No, no, of course not.
只是去别的地方交往
Just have your relationship someplace else.
那我可得指出  我忍气吞声整整八个月
May I point out that for eight long months,
忍受你女朋友在咱家
I suffered in silence as your female companion
大声唱跑调的乡村音乐
filled our apartment with her off-key country music caterwauling,
毫不知羞地在咱客厅
the unappetizing spectacle of her grinding a pumice stone
用浮石磨长满老茧的脚
against her calloused feet in our living room,
一夜接一夜地看
and night after night of uninformative
毫无内涵的电视剧《泽西海滩》
TV documentaries about the Jersey Shore.
忍气吞声
Suffered in silence?
没错
Yes.
我希望你也能这么做
And I'd thank you to do the same.
有没有搞错  忍气吞声
Reall-- Silence?!
落基山脉清凉的泉水
Nothing makes beer taste better
最能带出啤酒的味道
than cool clear Rocky Mountain spring water.
话说  落基山脉在哪啊
Where are the Rocky Mountains, anyway?
费城[实际不是]
Philadelphia.
真的吗
Really?
我以为在西部呢
I thought they were out West someplace.
这样想  拉杰
Think about it, Raj.
电影《洛奇》的故事发生在哪里
Where did the movie Rocky take place?
费城
Philadelphia.
我明白了
Okay, now I get it.
这就是咱的计划吗
So this is the plan?
从今天起
From now on,
我们就藏这里躲避谢米吗
we're just gonna hide out in here to avoid the Shamy?
我觉得这里很舒服
I'm very comfortable here.
佩妮亲爱的  再给我来一剂"万灵弹"吧
Penny, dear, why don't you shoot another silver bullet my way?
自己拿去
Get one yourself.
某人吃了泼妇药哦
Ooh, somebody's been taking bitchy pills.
老天  他喝了酒真混蛋
God, he's an ass when he drinks.
他没喝酒也混蛋
Oh, he's an ass when he doesn't.
你只是没听到
You just don't hear it.
我们得考虑谢米恋
Think we need to start entertaining the possibility
发展数年的可能性
that the Shamy could go on for years.
那样的话  佩妮得装卫星电视
Well, if that's the case, Penny will have to get satellite TV
而且每周吸一吸灰尘
and maybe once a week run a vacuum through this place.
你不是要跟谢尔顿谈吗
I thought you were going to talk to Sheldon.
-谈了  -他怎么说
- I did.  - Well, what'd he say?
他指出他过去有点必须
Well, he pointed out that he kinda sorta had to...
忍受你
put up with you.
有点必须
Kinda sorta had to?
我没同意他的说法
I didn't agree with him.
你帮我反驳了吧
Well, you defended me, right?
我试了  不过
I tried, but...
他说的理由太充分了
...he made a fairly well-reasoned argument.
你磨得不对
You're not doing that right.
什么
What?
给我
Gimme.
-不要  -相信我
- No.  - Trust me.
-不要  -我一直帮我妈磨脚
- No!  - I do this for my mom all the time.
看到没
See?
要顺着纹路摩
With the grain.
哇  确实好很多
Wow, that is better.
改天  你要是得了静脉曲张
And someday, when you have varicose veins,
我再教你怎么推拿
I'll show you how to massage them.
天呐  没有下次了
Oh, God, never again.
你的"没有下次"应该是指不再
I assume by "never again," you mean never again will you drink
喝完佩妮的啤酒后跑去加油站
all of Penny's beer, then run down to the gas station
买两瓶40s啤酒  一盒肉条
for a couple of 40s, a box of Slim Jims
还有最新一期的《孟买美妞翘臀》吧
and the latest issue of Bombay Badonkadonks.
人家想家了嘛
I was homesick.
当晚最精彩的就是你展示
The highlight of the evening was when you showed us
你的宝莱坞霹雳舞技
your Bollywood break dancing skills.
你这样很没礼貌
That's very offensive.
没错  我们当时也这么想
Yeah, we all thought so.
晕
Oh, no.
怎么了
What?
约翰和洋子来了[列侬夫妇]
It's John and Yoko.
更像洋子和洋子
More like Yoko and Yoko.
大家好
Greetings. Hey.
我带了艾米来
I brought Amy here
看看我的工作
to show her some of the work I'm doing.
对于理论工作来说  很不错了
It's very impressive, for theoretical work.
我好像察觉出一点屈就的意味
Do I detect a hint of condescension?
抱歉  我说得太间接了吗
I'm sorry, was I being too subtle?
我是指跟神经生物学
I meant compared to the real-world applications
在现实中的应用相比  理论物理就是
of neurobiology, theoretical physics is--
怎么说好呢  小巫见大巫
what's the word I'm looking for?-- hmm, cute.
你这是暗指神经生物学家的成就
Are you suggesting the work of a neurobiologist
例如巴宾斯基  能上升到物理学家
like Babinski could ever rise to the significance
例如克拉克·麦克斯韦或狄拉克的层面
of a physicist like Clark Maxwell or Dirac?
直截了当地说
I'm stating it outright.
巴宾斯基把狄拉克当早餐
Babinski eats Dirac for breakfast
再排泄出克拉克·麦克斯韦
and defecates Clarke-Maxwell.
你给我收回那话
You take that back.
绝不
Absolutely not.
我和同事们正在绘制
My colleagues and I are mapping
神经基质  有利于
the neurological substrates that subserve
促进全球信息处理
global information processing,
这种研究既要求认知推理
which is required for all cognitive reasoning,
也包括科学探索  由此事实可见
including scientific inquiry, making my research ipso facto
我的研究在认知序列上更高一层
prior in the ordo cognoscendi.
这就说明比他的研究更高级
That means it's better than his research,
由此可推  当然也胜过你们
and by extension, of course, yours.
不好意思  我的大脑
I'm sorry, I'm-I'm still trying
还停留在理解排泄克拉克·麦克斯韦上
to work on the defecating Clark Maxwell, so...
不好意思  但是统一场理论
Excuse me, but a grand unified theory,
在一定程度上解释了万物
insofar as it explains everything,
由此事实可见  也能解释神经生物学
will ipso facto explain neurobiology.
是没错  但要是我成功了
Yes, but if I'm successful,
我就能绘制和再现你演算出
I will be able to map and reproduce your thought processes
统一场理论的思维加工过程
in deriving a grand unified theory,
因此  你的结论也得纳入我的范式
and therefore, subsume your conclusions under my paradigm.
那是卑劣的心理主义
That's the rankest psychologism,
早在19世纪90年代就被费雷格
and was conclusively revealed as hogwash
板上钉钉为是胡言乱语
by Gottlob Frege in the 1890s!
看来我们陷入了僵局
We appear to have reached an impasse.
同意
I agree.
我决定立即终止我俩的关系
I move our relationship terminate immediately.
赞同
Seconded.
还有异议吗
There being no objections...
那么立即执行
...the motion carries.
日安  艾米·菲拉·福勒
Good day, Amy Farrah Fowler.
日安  谢尔顿·库珀
Good day, Sheldon Cooper.
女人哈
Women, huh?
没法和她们过日子
Can't live with them,
也没法反驳她们的各种假设
can't successfully refute their hypotheses.
上帝保佑
Amen to that.
好呀  谢尔顿
Hey, Sheldon.
你好
Hello.
听说你和艾米分手了
I hear you broke up with Amy.
说"分手"的话就说明她是我女朋友
A breakup would imply she was my girlfriend.
她是个女孩  曾经是我朋友
She was a girl who was my friend
现在她还是个女孩  但不是我朋友了
who is now a girl who is not my friend.
听着像史上最烂乡村民谣
Wow. That's like the worst country song ever.
你感觉如何
So, how are you doing?
什么感觉
Regarding what?
和艾米分手
Amy.
我不懂
I don't follow.
分手...不管你怎么叫  总是很难受的
Well, breakups-- or whatever the hell this is-- can be tough.
佩妮  放心  我没事
Penny, I assure you, I'm fine.
我和艾米只是纯粹智力上的关系
My relationship with Amy was purely intellectual,
没有丝毫感情色彩
There were no emotional bonds,
所以我也没有任何痛苦
the severing of which would cause me any discomfort.
这段关系只是失去效用罢了
The relationship simply outlived its utility,
我也像从前一样继续生活
and I'm continuing on with my life as before.
好吧  不错
Okay. Good.
我得先走了  要去买一只小猫咪
Now, if you'll excuse me, I'm off to buy a pussycat.
这事儿必须跟你们说一下
I gotta tell you guys,
我有点担心谢尔顿
I'm a little worried about Sheldon.
我们都有点担心谢尔顿
We're all a little worried about Sheldon.
我是说自从谢米恋搁浅后
No, I mean since the Shamy hit a reef.
我还以为你是一概而论呢
Oh, I thought you were just making a generalization:
"我担心谢尔顿  可能他某天"
"You know, I'm worried about Sheldon
会因为在咖啡馆吃不到酸橙果冻
"someday setting off a low-yield nuclear device
就去引爆一个低爆炸力核装置
because the cafeteria ran out of lime Jell-O."
搁浅是啥意思
What does "hit a reef" mean?
一拍两散
Uh, went splitsville.
啥
Pardon?
就是"屎了"
Turned to boom-boom.
我觉得谢尔顿真的很想念艾米
I think Sheldon really misses Amy.
你该把你的那本《孟买美妞翘臀》借给他
You should lend him your copy of Bombay Badonkadonks.
他找了只猫作伴
He got a cat to keep him company.
不是吧
You're kidding.
他上哪儿都带着
He takes it everywhere:
不管是卧室还是洗手间
to bed, to the bathroom.
他带猫咪用便壶吗
He takes the kitty to the potty?
我们不是说好不用这词儿了么
I thought we discussed the P-word.
别想着改变我  老兄
Don't try to change me, dude.
哥就是哥
I am what I am.
先生们
Oh, gentlemen.
不给我们介绍下
Hey. Aren't you going to introduce us
你的小伙伴吗
to your little friend?
不好意思
My apologies.
拉杰  霍华德  这位是罗伯特·奥本海默博士
Raj, Howard, I'd like you to meet Dr. Robert Oppenheimer.
你好
Hello. Hi.
失陪一下
Now, if you'll excuse me,
原子弹之父现在要来一碟牛奶
the father of the atomic bomb wants a saucer of milk.
我懂了  的确该担心谢尔顿
Okay, I get it. We're worried about Sheldon.
是吧
Yeah.
回来了
Hey.
不是吧
Oh, no.
奥本海默太孤单了
Robert Oppenheimer was lonely.
所以你要把整个曼哈顿计划的人都找来吗
So you decided to get the whole Manhattan Project?
对  这位是恩里科·费米  理查德·费曼
Yes. This is Enrico Fermi, Richard Feynman,
爱德华·泰勒
Edward Teller,
奥托·弗里希
Otto Frisch
还有犀利哥
and Zazzles.
什么鬼名字
Zazzles?
我本想给他取名为赫尔曼·冯·赫尔姆霍兹
I was going to name him Hermann von Helmholtz,
但他实在太犀利了
but he's so zazzy.
好吧  我们得谈谈
Okay, we need to talk.
谈什么
About what?
猫呗  谢尔顿
Cats, Sheldon.
显然艾米走后  你很难受
You're clearly upset about Amy being gone,
所以你想用一堆猫来代替她
and you're trying to replace her with a bunch of cats.
-一群猫  -啥
- Clowder. - What?
不用一堆  而要用一群  或者是一窝子
A group of cats is a clowder. Or a glaring.
好吧  我懂了
Okay, yeah, fine.
既然我们现在与猫为伍
It's the kind of thing you ought to know
我觉得有必要给你扫盲一下
now that we have one.
很好很强大  我的意思是
Terrific. My point is, you need to face up
你得坦然面对这次分手
to what you're feeling with this breakup.
这不是分手
It wasn't a breakup.
那样的话就说明她是我女朋友
A breakup would imply that Amy was my girlfriend.
好吧  我知道了  她不是你女朋友
Okay, I got it, I got it; she's not your girlfriend.
听我说
Now listen to me.
我知道孤单一人的感觉
I know about loneliness.
也明白要借其它事物来寻求安慰
I know about trying to replace someone with other stuff.
我那会和佩妮分手后  我又重新开始拉大提琴
When I broke up with Penny, I got back into my cello,
还搭了不少模型火箭
I built a bunch of model rockets,
我还买了举重手套和五磅重的哑铃
I got those weightlifting gloves and that five-pound dumbbell.
你那不叫分手  是佩妮甩了你
You didn't break up, she dumped you.
她才没甩了我
She didn't dump me.
这是互相的
It was mutual!
我就在场  是她甩了你
I was there. She dumped you.
好吧  随你吧
Okay, fine.
跟猫一起住吧
Live with cats.
跟我南希姨妈一样
Be like my Aunt Nancy.
她就跟几十只猫一起住
She had dozens of them.
你知道她死后怎么样了吗  猫把她给吃了
And do you know what happened after she died? They ate her.
不用再跟说服我喜欢猫了  莱纳德
You don't have to sell me on cats, Leonard.
我已经喜欢了
I'm already a fan.
好了小家伙们  谁想来吃点珍喜猫罐头
All right, fellas, who's in the mood for Fancy Feast?
这可一点都不喜人
Well, that's not fancy at all.
你好  库珀夫人  谢谢你赶来
Hi, Mrs. Cooper. Thanks for coming.
他人呢
Where is he?
在他卧室
He's in his bedroom.
你在电话里说的
Now, when you said on the phone
他跟个女孩分手了  是指真的女孩吧
he broke up with a girl, you meant an actual girl,
不是什么你们在实验室造出来的那种
not something you kids whipped up in a lab?
不  是真的人
No, she's real.
他们做了违反教规的事吗
Did they sin?
不  不是那样的
No, no, it's not like that.
是...
It's, uh...
我不知道怎么描述
I don't know what it's like.
但有些事  请你作好心理准备
But there is something I should prepare you for.
放心吧莱纳德  他是我一手拉扯大的
Oh, relax, Leonard, I have raised that boy.
最好的我见过  最坏的我也见过
I've seen him at his best, I've seen him at his worst.
没什么能让我吃惊的了
There's nothing he can do that'll surprise me.
话别说这么早
Hold on to that thought.
请进
Come in.
吃惊吧
Surprise.
妈  真是意外之喜
Mom, what an unexpected pleasure.
天  好大一股味
My, my, that's a powerful smell.
向你引见奥本海默  弗里希  潘诺夫斯基
I'd like you to meet Oppenheimer, Frisch, Panofsky,
费曼  维斯可夫
Feynman, Weisskopf...
好了  我明白了
Yeah, I get it.
你养了很多猫
You got a lot of cats
还给它们起了可爱的犹太名字
and you gave 'em cute Jewish names.
你来这干嘛
What are you doing here?
莱纳德打电话给我的
Leonard called.
他说你为伊人消得人憔悴
And he said that you were pining for a young lady.
那太可笑了
Oh, that's preposterous.
我才没有为谁憔悴
I'm not pining over anyone.
哦小羊排  我的说法或许不合适
Oh, lambchop, we can quibble what to call it,
但我们都同意  这事儿让人毛骨悚然
but I think we can both agree it's creepy.
我才不同意
I do not agree.
猫是很好的伙伴
Cats make wonderful companions.
不会跟你吵  也不会质疑你的才智权威
They don't argue or question my intellectual authority,
还有这个小家伙
and this little guy here,
你们会发现它实在太犀利了
I think you'll find to be quite zazzy.
你真该早点打给我的
You should have called sooner.
谢利  吃饭了
Shelly! Dinner's ready!
来了
Coming!
不许带猫
No cats!
她来这干嘛
What is she doing here?
我打给她的
I called her.
你妈妈认为
Your mother thinks
你可能正因我失魂落魄
you might be losing your mind over me.
作为神经生物学家  我很好奇
As a neurobiologist, I was curious.
放心  我心智完全正常
Well, rest assured, I am in full possession of my faculties.
25只猫
25 cats!
上帝保佑你  亲爱的
Oh, God bless you, dear.
谢尔顿  坐下  我们谈谈
Sheldon, sit down. Let's talk.
好吧  但不许骗我
All right, but you're not fooling me.
每次你说我们谈谈
Whenever you say we have to talk,
都只许你说我听
it means you want me to listen.
那就闭嘴
Then stop talking.
是  长官
Yes, ma'am.
我找艾米过来的原因
Now, the reason I called Amy over was
是想看看她是哪种人
to find out what type of person she is.
跟她聊了一会后
And after chatting a bit,
我不得不说  虽然她是个
I have to say that while she is a
绝对  特殊的女士
perfectly unique young woman,
你们俩完全不适合对方
you two are definitely not suited for each other.
这结论真奇怪
That's a peculiar conclusion.
不管以任何标准来衡量  艾米都比我认识的任何人
By any standard, Amy is more similar to me
跟我更像
than anyone I've ever met.
抱歉谢利  我看不出来
Oh, I'm sorry, Shelly, I can't see it.
你看不看得出来没关系
Well, whether you see it or not is irrelevant.
我也看不到亚原子粒子
I can't see subatomic particles,
但不论任何  它们就是存在的
but nevertheless, they're there.
绝妙的观点
Excellent point.
且是物理学观点
A physics point.
讲得好
Touche
别卖弄拉丁话了
Well, putting aside the pig Latin,
很高兴看到
it's a good thing that
你们决定分手
you two decided to end the relationship
就省得我来拆散你们了
so I didn't have to end it for you.
艾米  再三考虑之后
Amy, after consideration,
我觉得我们可能决定得太草率了
I believe we may have acted rashly.
我建议我们重新开始
I propose we resume our relationship
并尝试解决双方差异的障碍
and attempt to resolve our differences.
除非你认可  我俩之间
I'll agree to that only if you'll stipulate
80%的障碍都是你造成的
that 80% of our difficulties were caused by you.
-我只认可占40%  -你占65%
- I'll go as high as 40. - Sixty-five.
成交
Done.
你明白我们继续的话
You understand that moving forward,
我们得面对我妈并不认可你的现实
we deal with the fact that my mother does not approve of you?
我明白  我发现扮演个
I do. I find being cast
坏女孩的角色  竟让我很兴奋
in the role of bad girl oddly titillating.
想看看我的猫吗
Would you like to see my cats?
想  我喜欢猫
I would. I love cats.
它们是独善其身的典范
They're the epitome of indifference.
你会发现犀利哥有点烦人
Ah, then you may find Zazzles a little cloying.
我可算看出来了
I saw what you did there.
他一向自以为聪明
He thinks he's such a smarty pants.
其实跟其他人没什么不同
He's no different from any man.
你让他们别去做什么
You tell 'em not to do something,
他们就想做什么
certainly that's all  they want to do.
要不是我让我弟弟矮胖墩
If I hadn't told my brother Stumpy
别用手去清理碎木机
not to clear out the wood chipper by hand,
他就不会有这外号  还是爱德华了
we'd still be calling him Edward.
还有  你坐着别动
Now, don't you move.
我来把菜搬过来
I'll bring over all the food.
不不不  我来就行
No, no, no, I can do it.
真是太给力了
Well, isn't that sweet?
谢谢你  艾米
Thank you, Amy.
给  你的猫
Here's your cat.
还有你的20美元
And here's your $20.
下一个
Next!
谢谢你  艾米
Thank you, Amy.
给你你的猫
Here's your cat.
还有你的20美元
And here's your $20.
下一个
Next.